Marvin Carmack papers, 1920-2007 C503
Indiana University Archives
Marvin Carmack papers
1920-2007
1936-1978
Indiana University Archives
Carmack, Marvin, 1913-2010
C503
18.4 cubic feet 19 boxes
Marvin Carmack was a professor of chemistry at Indiana University who specialized in organic chemistry and the study of lithospermum ruderale, among other research interests. The collection consists of Carmack's personal and professional correspondence, extensive research notes from his two university appointments and numerous private laboratory work, teaching materials from a variety of classes he taught as well as research notes from some of his students.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Biographical Note
Born in 1913 in Dana (Vermillion County), Indiana, Marvin Carmack attended the University of Illinois and received an A.B. degree in Chemistry with honors in 1937. After completing both M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in Organic Chemistry at the University of Michigan in 1940, where he studied carcinogenic hydrocarbons, Dr. Carmack became a research associate at the University of Illinois, working on the chemistry of Senicio and Crotolaria alkaloids.
Professor Carmack began teaching at the University of Pennsylvania in 1941 as the Towne Instructor in Chemistry. He became Professor of Chemistry in 1951. During World War II, Dr. Carmack worked on contract with the National Defense Research Committee on high explosives and later on anti-malarial agents. Following the war, he began extensive studies in the field of organic sulfur chemistry. Awarded a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1949, he spent the year in Zurich, Switzerland. He later held a Fulbright Fellowship at the Commonwealth and Industrial Research Office in Australia.
In 1953, Dr. Carmack accepted a position at Indiana University as Professor of Chemistry. The offer of professorship arose after Carmack attended the First International Conference on Organic Sulfur Chemistry hosted by Indiana University. Impressed by the University's administration and after meeting with then-Chemistry Department chairman, Harry G. Day, Carmack decided to move back to his home state. He formally retired from Indiana University in 1978, although he continued to work and conduct research for several more years. Indeed, Dr. Carmack remained involved with the Indiana Association of Science, undertaking a research project in the early 1990s on George Hale, an Indiana scientist who helped to develop the explosive known as RDX. (George Hale's papers are also held by the IU Archives.)
Dr. Carmack's major research contributions focused on natural products and organosulfur chemistry. In the former area, his internationally recognized research detailed the chemistry of alkaloids and proof of structure of the active principle of Lithospernum Ruderale, the agent of fertility control used by the American Indians. His studies of organosulfur chemistry elucidated the spectral properties of sulfur compounds and the mechanism of the Willgerodt reaction.
In addition to academic work, Professor Carmack worked as a consultant to Abbott Laboratories, DuPont Company, and the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. He was also a member of Phi lambda upsilon, the National Chemistry Honor Society, and Sigma Xi, a scientific research society.
Dr. Carmack died on July 6, 2010.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Correspondence, Research, Teaching (further organized into two subseries of Student Work and Lecture Notes), and Biographical.
Scope and Content Note
The Biographical series, 1929-1957, contain personal documents and materials gathered by Carmack, mostly from his high school and college years as well as an address book.
The Correspondence series, 1928-2001, is arranged primarily chronologically but also contains folders of correspondence with a single person or a single topic. The letters consist primarily of Carmack's professional correspondence with colleagues at IU and at other universities. There is, however, personal correspondence interfiled, especially pre-1940, when Carmack's family wrote frequently during his college years.
The Research series, 1920-2007, forms the bulk of the collection. Dr. Carmack worked at several private laboratories - including Los Alamos and DuPont - conducting research and doing consulting work. Files related to that research and his findings are located in this series. Also present are extensive notes and materials related to his personal investigation of the Willgerodt reaction, lithospermum ruderale, and other organic chemistry research. Carmack's notes and finished article about George Hale are included in the collection. This series also contains notes from his involvement in professional organizations and various committees he served on while at Indiana University. There is also a 1988 IU name badge as well as two audio cassette tapes from a 1977 lecture in the series.
The Teaching series, 1936-1993, contains two subseries, Student Work, 1942-1965 and Lecture Notes, 1936-1978. The Student Work contains research and laboratory notebooks from his students, both undergraduate and graduate. At this time the sub-series is closed but may be made available with advance notice so that the Archivist may review the specific files requested. Dr. Carmack retained most of his teaching and lecture notes, which include blank quizzes, tests, handouts, and other related material. Where possible, the material is arranged by course number and name.
Separated Material
One glass vial that previously contained the chemical, thiouracil (lederle).
Photographs Pulled: Dozens of photographs were removed from the collection and are now stored with the Archives Photographs Collection. Photographs include images of Dr. Carmack in laboratories and lecturing, personal photographs, student portraits, and images related to his research on George C. Hale. Also included in separated photographs is a spiral bound yearbook from 1949 for Harrison Laboratory at the University of Pennsylvania. Approximately two dozen rolls of negative film containing images of research documents and lectures are also present in the collection.
Related Material
Additional publications and research materials may be accessed in IUScholarworks: http://scholarworks.iu.edu/
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database: http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/
Acquisition Information
2010/096
Chemistry--Study and teaching (Higher)--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources; Chemistry teachers--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources; Carmack, Marvin, 1913-2010 -- Archives; Carmack, Marvin, 1913-2010 -- Correspondence; Indiana University. Department of Chemistry -- Faculty -- Archives
- Biographical, 1929-1957 (Box 1)
  - Address book, undated (Box 1)
  - Childhood Educational Materials, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Chemistry 61 Notes, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Coursework, 1937-1939 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Dissertation, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Dissertation Bibliography, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Graduate School Committee on Language Requirements, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Graduate School Council, 1955-1957 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Thesis First Draft, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Personal Files, 1947-1952 (Box 1)
  - Leave of Absence, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Class Notes, undated (Box 1)
    General
    (5 folders)
  - Undergraduate Materials, 1934-1937 (Box 1)
    (2 folders)
  - Undergraduate Research Reports, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Work (Box 1)
    - 1938 (Box 1)
    - undated (Box 1)
  - War Ration Booklet, 1944 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1928-2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 1)
    - 1935 (Box 1)
    - 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937 (Box 1)
    - 1938 (Box 1)
    - 1939 (Box 1)
    - 1940 (Box 2)
      (4 folders)
    - 1941 (Box 2)
    - 1942 (Box 2)
    - 1943 (Box 2)
    - 1944 (Box 2)
    - 1945 (Box 2)
    - 1946 (Box 2)
    - 1947 (Box 2)
    - 1948 (Box 2)
    - 1949 (Box 2)
    - 1950 (Box 2)
    - 1951 (Box 2)
    - 1952 (Box 2)
      (3 folders)
    - 1953 (Box 2)
      - January-February (Box 2)
      - March (Box 2)
      - April (Box 2)
      - May (Box 2)
      - June (Box 2)
      - July (Box 2)
      - August (Box 2)
      - September-October (Box 2)
      - November (Box 2)
      - December (Box 2)
      - undated, circa 1953 (Box 2)
    - 1954 (Box 3)
    - 1955 (Box 3)
    - 1956 (Box 3)
    - 1957 (Box 3)
    - 1958 (Box 3)
    - 1959 (Box 3)
    - 1960 (Box 3)
    - 1961 (Box 3)
    - 1962 (Box 3)
    - 1964 (Box 3)
    - 1966 (Box 3)
    - 1967 (Box 3)
    - 1968 (Box 3)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 3)
    - 1977 (Box 3)
    - 2001 (Box 3)
    - undated (Box 3)
  - Amoore Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Arthur D. Little, Inc., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Dastoli Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - DuPont Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 3)
  - Edward, John T., 1991 (Box 3)
  - Family Correspondence (Box 3)
    - 1928-1931 (Box 3)
    - 1943-1950 (Box 3)
  - General Indiana University Correspondence, 1941-1980 (Box 3)
    (Chiefly 1952-1953 relating to his appointment at IU.)
  - Indiana University Unfinished Business Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - International Conference Correspondence, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Lecture Correspondence (Box 4)
    - 1944-1951 (Box 4)
    - 1952-1958 (Box 4)
  - Long, Dale Correspondence, 1951-1962 (Box 4)
  - Lorenz, Walter, 1986-1992 (Box 4)
  - Mayo, Dana, 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - Menadione (Hykinone Structure) Correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 4)
  - Novotny, Milos, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Organic Chemists' Club Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
  - Osgan, Nash Correspondence, 1954 (Box 4)
  - RDX Research Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Rees, Richard, Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Suspense Folder Correspondence, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Unanswered mail, 1953 (Box 4)
  - University of Pennsylvania Correspondence, 1947-1952 (Box 4)
  - Weinberg, Eugene, Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Willgerodt Reaction Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 4)
  - Wiesler, Donald, 1997 (Box 4)
- Research, 1920-2007 (Box 4)
  - Abbott Laboratories (Box 4)
    - 1944-1946 (Box 4)
    - 1945 (Box 4)
    - 1949 (Box 4)
  - Abbott Laboratories Materials (Box 4)
    - 1945-1947 (Box 4)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - Abbott Laboratories Visit (Box 4)
    - 1947 (Box 4)
    - 1948 (Box 4)
  - Absorption Spectrum Material, undated (Box 4)
  - Academic Appointment Materials, 1951-1956 (Box 4)
  - Acid-Base Relations Materials, undated (Box 4)
  - Advances in Heterocyclic Chemistry, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Alkaloid Material, 1933-1939 (Box 4)
  - Alkaloids Research, 1981-1989 (Box 4)
  - Alkaloids Natural Products Notes, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Amine bases, Basic strengths, undated (Box 5)
  - Ammonia Department Research Laboratory Notes, 1948 (Box 5)
  - AAUP Committee on Faculty Economic Status, 1956-1958 (Box 5)
  - American Chemical Society, 1952 (Box 5)
  - American Chemical Society Committee on Professional Training, 1956 (Box 5)
  - American Chemical Society Baton Rouge Meeting, 1990 (Box 5)
  - American Chemical Society Honolulu Meeting, 1979 (Box 5)
  - American Petroleum Institute Research, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Army Chemical Center, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
  - Association of IU Chemists, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
  - Baer, John E., 1947-1949 (Box 5)
  - Bachmann Memorial Session, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Baizer, Manuel M., 1944-1947 (Box 5)
  - Baird Associates' Infrared Spectrophotometer, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Behforouz Materials (Box 5)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - 1974 (Box 5)
  - Benzothiadiazole Research, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Bibliography List of Publications, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Bioassays on SKF Lithospermum, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Biogenesis of 5-Alkyl-resorcinols, undated (Box 5)
  - Brucea Javonica Slides, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Buxus Alkaloids Research, 1954-1958 (Box 5)
  - Calendar, 1956-1957 (Box 5)
  - Cancer Chemotherapy, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Catalytic Hydrogenation Benzalhyde, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - Caralien Progress Report, undated (Box 5)
  - Cavalier, Liebe, 1945-1949 (Box 5)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Chemical and Engineering News, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Chemical Warfare Laboratories, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Abstracts, 1926-1949 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Article Citations, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Conference Notes, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Data, 1945-1951 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Department Colloquium Committee, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Instrument Catalogues (Box 5)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 5)
    - 1953 (Box 5)
    - 1957 (Box 5)
    - Undated (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Laboratory Equipment and Brochures, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Laboratory Supply Catalogues, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Literature Search Citations (Box 5)
    - 1979 (Box 5)
    - 1981 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Machine Shop Expenses, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry Research (Box 5)
    - 1945-1951 (Box 5)
    - 1949-1985 (Box 6)
    - Undated (Box 6)
  - Chemistry Research Articles (Box 6)
    - 1937-1956 (Box 6)
    - 1956-1963 (Box 6)
    - 1962-1965 (Box 6)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - Committee on Graduate Students, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
  - Computer Center Statistical Analysis, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Conference Travel Materials, 1942-1967 (Box 6)
  - Confirmation of Biopolymers, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Cordes-Schaeffer Book (photocopy), undated (Box 6)
  - Counter Current Apparatus, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Crotalaria-Senecio Alkaloids Post-Doctoral Research, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Cystinosis Research, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Davis, Collins, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Delphinium Alkaloid Reports, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Delphinium Alkaloid Research, 1956-1958 (Box 6)
  - Delphinium Research, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Deltaline Communication, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Deltaline Reserach, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Department of Agriculture Materials, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Department of HEW Grant Application, 1954 (Box 6)
  - DuPont Ammonia Department, 1947-1949 (Box 6)
  - DuPont Expense Account (Box 6)
    - 1953-1958 (Box 6)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Explosives Department, 1955-1960 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Film Department, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Grasselli Materials, 1951-1960 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Materials, 1952-1960 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Polychemicals Department, 1950-1960 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Polychemicals, 1955 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Polychemicals Research Division Notes (Box 7)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 7)
    - 1953 (Box 7)
    - 1954 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Research Notes, 1949 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Rayon Department, 1951 (Box 7)
  - DuPont Viscose Rayon, 1949-1951 (Box 7)
  - Eastern Regional Research Lab, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Enzymes Antimalarials, 1942 (Box 7)
  - Erythrina Colloquium Notes, undated (Box 7)
  - Flaks Report, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Frank Gurd Memoir, 2007 (Box 7)
  - Gem-dithiols Material, 1959 (Box 7)
  - German Chemical Processes Report, 1944-1945 (Box 7)
  - Goland, Philip P., 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Grasselli Chemicals (Box 7)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 7)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 7)
  - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 7)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 7)
    - 1955 (Box 7)
  - Hale Biography, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Hale Memorial Article and Research Notes, 1983-1991 (Box 7)
  - Hale Notes, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Hale RDX Lecture, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Hale Research Materials from Owens, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Henry Eyring 1977 Lecture Tapes (cassette tapes), 1977-1990 (Box 7)
  - Hofstetter, Alfred Graduate Fellowship Materials, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Holothurin Literature, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Honorary Societies, 1939-1954 (Box 8)
  - Honoring the Scholars Lecture, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Indiana Academy of Science Annual Meeting, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Indiana Academy of Science George Hale Presentation, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Indiana Academy of Science Hale Article and Research, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Infrared Spectrometer Laboratory, 1953-1956 (Box 8)
  - Infrared Spectrometer Notes (Box 8)
    - 1947-1951 (Box 8)
    - 1949 (Box 8)
  - IU Chemistry Professors' Biographies, 1952 (Box 8)
  - IU Chemical Report (Box 8)
    - Number 1, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 2, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 3-4, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 5, 1959 (Box 8)
  - IU Lab Plans, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - IU Report to SKF (Box 8)
    - Number 4, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 5, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 6, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 7, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Number 8, 1959 (Box 8)
  - IU Chemistry Department Rules and Regulations, 1955 (Box 8)
  - IU SKF Extraction Procedure for Lithosperm, 1958 (Box 8)
  - IUPAC Zurich Meeting, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Isolable Oxysufanes Research, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Journal of the American Chemistry Society, 1966-1967 (Box 8)
  - Kissinger, L.W., 1948-1949 (Box 8)
  - Koch Student Research, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Koshland Materials, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
  - Lacto bacillus casei Factor Article, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Laubach, G.D., 1947 (Box 8)
  - Leavitt, J.J., 1947 (Box 8)
  - Lenape Club, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Conference Planned Parenthood, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Paper (Loeser), 1956 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Progress Report, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Reports (Box 8)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 8)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Research, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Ruderale, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Ruderale Project Publications, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Lithospermum Ruderale literature negatives, 1941-1948 (Box 8)
  - Lockheed DIALOG Information Retrieval, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Long, Dale (Scully-Jones & Co.), 1947-1953 (Box 8)
  - Los Alamos Materials, 1951-1960 (Box 8)
  - Los Alamos Materials, 1951-1960 (Box 9)
  - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, 1952-1953 (Box 9)
  - Lubrizol Corporation, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Lupinus Sericeus Pursh Literature, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Mack Printing Company, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Martin Chemical Report, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Medicinal Chemistry Division ACS, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Menadione Paper, 1949 (Box 9)
  - Merck Patent Materials (Box 9)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 9)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 9)
  - Merck Research Materials (Box 9)
    - 1939 (Box 9)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 9)
  - Merck Sharp and Dohme Research Laboratories, 1957-1958 (Box 9)
  - Merrell Company Fellowship, 1943-1945 (Box 9)
  - Microbiological Systems Article, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Monsanto Research, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Name badge, 1988 (Box 9)
  - National Academy of Sciences Meeting Programs, 1956-1957 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council, 1958 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council Annual Report, 1956-1957 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council of Canada, 1947-1952 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council Fellowship Application, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council Materials (Box 9)
    - 1954-1956 (Box 9)
    - 1956-1958 (Box 9)
  - National Research Council Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Navy Office of Naval Research, 1947-1948 (Box 9)
  - Neubert Daton, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Neubert Graphs, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1950-1980 (Box 9)
  - Optical Activity of the Chiral Disulfide Group Research, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Optical Rotary Properties Research, 1954-1967 (Box 9)
  - Organic Chemistry (Box 9)
    - Report, 1946 (Box 9)
    - Research, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
    - Symposium, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Organic Chemists' Club, 1947-1949 (Box 9)
  - Organic Chemists' Club Dinners, 1945-1946 (Box 9)
  - Organic Compound Nomenclature, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Organic Qualitative Analysis (Box 10)
    - 1948 (Box 10)
    - 1952 (Box 10)
  - Oxidation Research, undated (Box 10)
  - Otto Meyerhof Tribute Essay, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Oxidation of Benzothiodiazole Article, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Oxynitration of Benzene to Nitrophenols, 1945 (Box 10)
  - P-Phenylenediamine Synthesis, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Paper Chromatography of Polymethylol Phenols, 1952 (Box 10)
  - PCB Research Material, 1991-1993 (Box 10)
  - Petroleum Bibliography, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Petroleum Research Fund Advisory Board, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Pheromones Research, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Philadelphia Organic Chemists' Club, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Physical Methods in Heterocyclic Chemistry, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Polychemicals, 1950-1952 (Box 10)
  - Polysulfides, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Postdoctoral Recommendations, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - Prelog Celebration, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Price, Sir Robert and Joyce Correspondence, 1972-1993 (Box 10)
  - Primiano Student Research, 1944 (Box 10)
  - Professional Appointments, 1941-1944 (Box 10)
  - Project Big Ben Materials, 1952-1953 (Box 10)
  - Publications (Box 10)
    - 1941-1950 (Box 10)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 10)
  - Public Health Service (Box 10)
    - Budgets, 1958 (Box 10)
    - Research Grant, 1958 (Box 10)
    - Project, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Pyrroline Rings Research, undated (Box 10)
  - Raymond, Samuel, 1947 (Box 10)
  - Research Department Explosive (RDX) (Box 10)
    - Article Citations, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Bachmann Papers, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
    - Duplicate Copies, 1949-1960 (Box 10)
    - Committee Files, 1944 (Box 10)
    - Committee Report, 1943 (Box 10)
    - Lecture for ACS, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Paper Drafts, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
    - Preparation Report, 1945 (Box 10)
    - Report on Cyclonite (Box 10)
      - 1942 (Box 10)
      - 1946 (Box 10)
    - Research Articles, 1948-1949 (Box 10)
    - Research Files (Box 10)
      - 1943 (Box 10)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 10)
      - 1959-1965 (Box 10)
      - 1973-1989 (Box 10)
    - Research Panel (British), 1944 (Box 10)
    - Research Panel (British), 1944 (Box 11)
    - Symposium at Indiana Academy of Science, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Wabash River Ordnance Plant, 1990 (Box 11)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Reprint Requests, 1956-1959 (Box 11)
  - Requisition Requests, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
  - Research Funds, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Research Materials (Box 11)
    - 1963-1968 (Box 11)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 11)
    - 1968 (Box 11)
  - Research Notes (Box 11)
    - 1938 (Box 11)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 11)
    - 1946 (Box 11)
    - 1947 (Box 11)
    - 1948 (Box 11)
  - Ring Cleavage Research, undated (Box 11)
  - Schoch, Jonathan, 1992 (Box 11)
  - Searle-SN-13616 Drug, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Seifriz, William, 1946-1947 (Box 11)
  - Shapp and Dohme Fellowships, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Sigma Xi, 1951-1953 (Box 11)
  - Sigma Xi Presidential Address, undated (Box 11)
  - Sigma Xi Society, 1955 (Box 11)
  - Smith, Kline, and French Fund, 1955 (Box 11)
  - Sparteine Lab Notebook, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Spectra Graphs (Box 11)
    - 1963 (Box 11)
    - Undated (Box 11)
  - Spurgeon, William M., 1947 (Box 11)
  - Specht, Edward H., 1945 (Box 11)
  - Stetter and Dierichs Article, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Stereochem of Steroids Research Material, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Stevioside Literature Survey, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Stevioside Literature Survey, 1949 (Box 12)
  - Stevioside Research (Box 12)
    - 1920-1931 (Box 12)
    - 1931-1948 (Box 12)
    - 1947-1955 (Box 12)
    - 1949 (Box 12)
  - Sulfur Reactions Notes, 1945 (Box 12)
  - Sulfur Conference, 1951 (Box 12)
  - Sulfur Book Wiley Publishers, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Sulfur Research Reprints, 1943-1948 (Box 12)
  - Synthesis of Penicillin Notes, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Synthesis of Some Naptholamines Article, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Synthetic Work, undated (Box 12)
  - Telephone Conversation with Sandra Beadles, undated (Box 12)
  - Thiadiazole ACS Paper, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Thiouracil (lederle), glass vial previously containing that chemical, undated (Box 12)
  - Towne School Curriculum Committee, 1949 (Box 12)
  - Travel Plans, 1967 (Box 12)
  - USDA, 1956 (Box 12)
  - USDA Plant Research, 1954 (Box 12)
  - UV Optical Activity of Crystals, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Von, Isaiah, 1947-1949 (Box 12)
  - Visitors to University of Pennsylvania, 1951 (Box 12)
  - Wagner, E.C., 1954-1956 (Box 12)
  - Wannamaker Chemical Company, 1944-1946 (Box 12)
  - War Manpower Commission, 1942-1943 (Box 12)
  - Willgerodt Patent Application, 1945-1949 (Box 12)
  - Willgerodt Reaction, 1947 (Box 12)
  - Willgerodt Reaction Articles (Box 12)
    - 1947-1972 (Box 12)
    - 1951-1978 (Box 12)
    - 1963-1967 (Box 12)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 12)
    - 1965-1970 (Box 12)
    - 1966-1973 (Box 12)
    - 1974 (Box 12)
    - Undated (Box 12)
  - Willgerodt Reaction Lectures (Box 12)